Qualification Profile

Ambitious and quick learning individual with an analytic approach to problem solving. Goal oriented and tenacious, continually striving to improve operations and deliver exceptional products for client and customers through a perceptive and shrewd understanding of the demands of said customers through adaptive operational procedures and innovative problem solving. Enthusiastic team player that can excel in collaborative and independent role.

Core Competencies

•	Qualitative research	•	Handling Proprietary information	•	Team leadership
•	Python	•	Billing and financial claim processing	•	Collaboration
•	MySQL	•	Operations Management	•	Report publication

Professional Experience

Kintetsu World Express, Inglewood, CA.

August 2022 - August 2023

Automated Manifest System Operations Lead

Swiftly promoted from associate to operational lead role overseeing and coordinating cargo recovery from LAX to CFS trucking warehouses while simultaneously training adjacent department members on operational procedures. Handled the transfer of proprietary documentation for customs clearance and maintained data collection of expenses and cargo details.

- Provided documentation for customs clearance and excelled at cargo recovery and customer communication for customers such as LG, Amer Sports and Henkel that improved company relationship and increased business
- Redesigned operational procedure by developing an improved excel sheet and changing operational decisions that lead to improved company performance and improved business relationship with Amer Sports by cutting back on our expenses by 20% and reducing their cost as a result.
- Stream lined formal and preliminary claim procedure using excel to automate mundane tasks which increased department productivity.

The University of California, Irvine, Irvine, CA.

September 2020 - December 2020

Research experience & publication

Collaborated in conducting research focused on potential chemical disasters, routine pollution and climate change impacts and planning in California communities.

- Used research processes and digital tools such as finding and interpreting local data from sources like CalEnviroScreen, EPA EJScreen, and the US Government Accounting Office
- Qualitative Social Science Methods; stakeholder and ethical analyses; report writing, including many data visualizations; bibliography development. The case studies are published at the links below:

 $\underline{\text{https://disaster-sts-network.org/content/eij-fall-2020-combo-disaster-case-study-riverside-count}}\\ \underline{\text{v-group-15}}$

Inglewood Unified School District (IUSD) Advisory Committee, Inglewood CA. May 2017- January 2018

Student and Community Representative

Assessed and advised on the reallocation of resources for IUSD contingent upon construction of SoFi stadium, and related properties.

- Analyzed collections of data representing projected student population, student displacement, and additional income from various real estate properties owned by Inglewood Unified School District
- Prevented the closure of a school and further loss of student population for the district after discovering a discrepancy in the data provided, which did not properly reflect the decrease of student enrollment if a property were sold.

Northrop Grumman El Segundo, CA.

February 2017 - May 2017

South Bay Promise Student Intern

As an intern I was given the opportunity to learn under the stress analysis team for the F/A-18 fighter jet. I completed stress analysis on the wing of the plane using autodesk inventor and other softwares. Based on my findings, I compared my results with a software developed by one of the engineers on the team meant to expedite the process in order to confirm its accuracy.

- Completed tasks using industry standard software at the time such as excel and autodesk
- Optimized the project manager's excel spreadsheet that represented project budgets, as a result
 the manager was better able to project the budget and requirements needed for the team he
 was overseeing.

Education and Technical Proficiencies

BACHELOR OF ARTS, POLITICAL SCIENCE UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, IRVINE * IRVINE, CA.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Test Driven Development (Pytest), Django, Bootstrap, MySQL, CSS, HTML, qualitative research, quantitative research, Calculus, Statistics, budgeting, risk management, command line, technical and fundamental analysis of business firms,

Languages: English, Spanish